
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'>
    <channel>

        <title>Lartunet</title>
        <link>https://lartu.net</link>
        <description>Lartu's Log of Interesting Things</description>
        <image>
            <url>https://lartu.net/files/rss.jpg</url>
            <title>Lartunet</title>
            <link>https://lartu.net</link>
        </image>
		<item>
			<title>Pickles and Rain</title>
			<link>https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-22.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink='false'>log_2021-05-22.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lartu]]></dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<h1>2021-05-22: Pickles and Rain</h1>

Yesterday I read <a href="https://www.raptitude.com/2010/07/your-lifestyle-has-already-been-designed/"" target=_blank>this article</a>
about how our routines (working all day and having a little free time
during the evening) are functional to consumerism. It may be that way.
It may not, I don't really care much. What I do care about is that
<i>that's</i> my routine. Every day the same four walls, same activities,
same everything.
<br><br>
This is not the first time I've noticed this, though. I visited my
grandparents about two months ago after a long year of not seeing
them during the 2020 quarantine. I had a lot of stuff to tell them:
I had moved by myself, I was cooking a lot, I had started taking
classes in a new university, etc. Lots of changes and news.
<br><br>
Then, a month later, I visited them again. This time, I had nothing
new to tell.
<br><br>
The same goes for visiting my parents. I see them once a week or so.
When I moved by myself I had a lot of things to tell them. Then,
week after week, nothing. I cooked some stuff, I went to the same
old shops, work, sleep, study. Eternal while true. I struggled trying
to find something to talk about. What's next?
I could do a lot more, why am I not doing so?
<br><br>
Well, I believe the main impediment right now is the COVID-19
pandemic. We've been quarantined. Again. And traveling abroad is not
particularly easy at this very moment. I live in a big city,
though. There <i>should</i> be things to do around here! Why am I not
partaking in that? Then again, the answer is the pandemic.
<br><br>
In any case, though, there are other things I should be able to do
to break the monotony. So I've started this log. I will try to do
something new now and then. And who knows, maybe I'll be able to
escape the oppressive cycle my life has turned into.
<br><br>
So, <b>what did I do today?</b>

<br><a href="https://lartu.net/images/M72J76.JPG"><img src ="https://lartu.net/images/c_M72J76.JPEG" title="M72J76" alt="Image: M72J76"></a><br>

Today it rained a lot. There's
a cyclone alert and everything. 
Sadly, I didn't take any pictures.
I didn't know I was going to write a log of my day.
In any case, given that we are to be
quarantined -and thanks to the weather- the streets were rather
empty. We went to the grocery store taking the longest possible
route, seizing the opportunity to discover our neighbourhood. I love
the way everything shines when it rains.
<br><br>
We even found some dumbells somebody had discarded on the street,
so we took them home. They were in perfect shape!
<br><br>
We came back home wet and cold after buying some veggies. I
cooked some soup and baked pumpkin, and we ate it
outside in the patio, under the rain-turned-drizzle. Cool
experience.

<br><a href="https://lartu.net/images/I03C35.JPG"><img src ="https://lartu.net/images/c_I03C35.JPEG" title="I03C35" alt="Image: I03C35"></a><br>

Having eaten and all, I pickled some onions and peppers and
left them in a cupboard to marinate. In a week or two they'll
be ready to eat.

<br><a href="https://lartu.net/images/Y43C23.JPG"><img src ="https://lartu.net/images/c_Y43C23.JPEG" title="Y43C23" alt="Image: Y43C23"></a><br>

I'm growing a leek. The rest of it went into the soup. Once it grows
new roots I'll plant it in a pot.

<br><br>

Also, I started reading <i>The Catcher in the Rye</i>, by J. D. Salinger.
My uncle had recommended it to me many times. He had even lent me his
copy at some point. I hadn't had the chance to read it, though.
I'm walfway through. Great book, the
way it's written reminds me a lot of how 
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Night_in_the_Woods"" target=_blank>Night in the Woods</a>
is written. That's never a bad thing.

<br><br>

Tomorrow I will try to go out and walk a little more. I can't go
out for <i>too long</i> because we've been requested to stay at home,
but somewhere close should be fine. Maybe to a park or to get some
take-away coffee.]]></description>
		</item>

    </channel>
</rss>
