<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
        <rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
            <channel>
                <title>Lartunet</title>
                <link>https://lartu.net</link>
                <description>Lartu's Log of Interesting Things</description>
                <image>
                    <url>https://lartu.net/files/rss.jpg</url>
                    <title>Lartunet</title>
                    <link>https://lartu.net</link>
                </image>
        		<item>
			<title>Log of the Last Weeks (Part I)</title>
			<link>https://lartu.net/log_2021-06-17.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink='false'>log_2021-06-17.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:03:00 -0300</pubDate>
			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lartu]]></dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<!-- RSS ARTICLE STARTS HERE -->
<h1>log of the last weeks (part i).</h1>

<p>I spent the last weeks super busy studying. I had tons of exams to sit for and reports to write, so I spent most of my time secluded and buried over mountains of digital paperwork. I, nevertheless, took some time out of each day to write a minimal log entry to remember what I had done. This entry is a collection, an anthology of sorts, of all the <i>interesting</i> things I've done over the past two to three weeks.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_G16V09.JPEG" title="G16V09" alt="Image: G16V09"><small>— G16V09  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/G16V09.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2362 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>Before we start, some technical details. I have created my own date notation. I've been using it for all my projects and notes, I find it really convenient<sup>1</sup> and easy to use. I use it in <a href="https://lartu.net/excal.html" >Excal</a>, I've used it in my diary entries, I use it when creating documents and folders and so I'll be using it here too. Mostly due to the fact that I have logged each day using this very notation.</p>

<p>It goes like this: all dates consist of five characters. Two digits for the date number. A digit for the month. Two digits for the year. Today is <b>17J21</b>, June 17, 2021. If the month letter is in UPPERCASE, then the year is in the 2000s. In this case, 2000 + 21 = 2021. If the letter is in lowercase, then the year is in the 1900s, in case I need to talk about the year I was born or something. I don't really care much about noting dates of any other century, but the system allows for other centuries if desired. First, each month is represented by a letter. The letters used come from the name of the month in Spanish.</p>

<ul>
<li><b>E</b> for January (Enero) <li><b>F</b> for February (Febrero) <li><b>M</b> for March (Marzo) <li><b>A</b> for April (Abril) <li><b>Y</b> for May (Mayo) <li><b>J</b> for June (Junio) <li><b>L</b> for July (July) <li><b>A</b> for August (Agosto) <li><b>S</b> for September (Septiembre) <li><b>O</b> for October (Octubre) <li><b>N</b> for November (Noviembre) <li><b>D</b> for December (Diciembre)</li>
</ul>

<p>23s95 is September 23, 1995. 21E05 is January 21, 2005. Etc. Any letters not used here (or characters or whatever) could be used to write down dates from other centuries. Maybe 13#45 could mean April 13, 1845. I don't really care much. Feel free to extend the system.</p>

<h1>29Y21</h1>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_C47T33.JPEG" title="C47T33" alt="Image: C47T33"><small>— C47T33  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/C47T33.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2222 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>I ate some hotcakes. The leek is growing in its pot. I also took some pictures.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_O37D65.JPEG" title="O37D65" alt="Image: O37D65"><small>— O37D65  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/O37D65.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2808 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<h1>30Y21</h1>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_P12R86.JPEG" title="P12R86" alt="Image: P12R86"><small>— P12R86  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/P12R86.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2098 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>We went out and ate some pizza. I mixed the order up when ordering and I ended up eating some vegetable pizza with white sauce. It was nice to try something new, I liked it. My parents videocalled us while we were out, so we had a little chat <i>al fresco</i>. That was quite fun. I also celebrated 10 years on Twitter, although I have probably activelly used the social network less than half of that time. I developed <a href="https://lartu.net/excal.html" >Excal</a> to keep track of my expenses (I used to use a giant spreadsheet, but I was getting tired of it and I needed something I could scale even further). This day I also spent the night up making sense of my expenses. In the end, though, everything was okay, but now I know what I waste money on and how much I have left (in average) each month, so I can spend more consciously.</p>

<p>I had a call with Tejo to define some aspects of the Eterspire animation system – which was a mess until he reworked it –, and watched a lot of The Nightmare Before Christmas clips. I loved that movie as a child, I didn't remember how much.</p>

<h1>30Y21</h1>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_U43G13.JPEG" title="U43G13" alt="Image: U43G13"><small>— U43G13  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/U43G13.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2624 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>We went to the supermarket to stock ourselves for the next weeks, but my shoulder was in terrible pain so we just bought things for the week. We bought some jalapenos and I cooked an amazing spicy pomarola sauce. I also bought a very tasty caesar salad wrap. It was my grandma's birthday, so I called her and we spent a while talking. She had had some health issues during the first half of the year, but she's doing better now, so that's both great news and a relief. It makes me really happy. The rest of the day was spent studying.</p>

<h1>01J21</h1>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_N14A28.JPEG" title="N14A28" alt="Image: N14A28"><small>— N14A28  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/N14A28.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1608 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>This day was also spent studying. I tried to organize my study around pomodoro timers, and I failed catastrophically at that. For the last days I've been experimenting with biphasic sleeping and adjusting to the new sleep patterns kept me quite drowzy. Nevertheless, at night – and specially between sleep periods – I could concentrate very easily.</p>

<p>I did have a hard time sleeping, though. My shoulder hurt like crazy.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_R06L85.JPEG" title="R06L85" alt="Image: R06L85"><small>— R06L85  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/R06L85.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1626 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>The pickles I had made <a href="https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-22.html" >about a week or so ago</a> were ready, so we opened them. They turned out great, delicious. I had also pickled some onions, but those were kept in their jars.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_O82J20.JPEG" title="O82J20" alt="Image: O82J20"><small>— O82J20  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/O82J20.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2313 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<h1>02J21</h1>

<p>I spent the better part of the day studying. Again. My shoulder kept hurting. At one point I couldn't tolerate it anymore and went to the hospital. My arm ended up in a cast and they gave me some painkillers.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_V62J96.JPEG" title="V62J96" alt="Image: V62J96"><small>— V62J96  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/V62J96.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1737 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>I cooked some patties with salad and pepper pickles. Sleeping with my shoulder like that was hard.</p>

<p>This night I had a weird dream. I was living in a Roblox-Lego-like world, and I had built a train and a plastic-flower garden. There, I met The Architect, an old supervillain with a green and purple leotard that could fly and had the power of creating branching buildings out of nowhere, that grew and twirled like vines. He had a mental-wave gun. When he shot me with it, I woke up.</p>

<p>During the rest of the night I drank some canned wine. I had never tried it. It was really nice. I also spent some time crawling the indienet, the independant internet of personal websites. I jumped from <a href="https://fdisk.space/" target=_blank>ƒdisk</a> to <a href="https://nchrs.xyz/" target=_blank>nchrs.xyz</a>, and there I found two marvellous stories: <a href="https://nchrs.xyz/site/a_thousand_marbles.html" target=_blank>A Thousand Marbles</a> and <a href="https://nchrs.xyz/site/the_egg.html" target=_blank>The Egg</a>. Both are quite short. Very recommended readings. I also found <a href="https://lieu.cblgh.org" target=_blank>Lieu</a>, a search engine for the <a href="https://merveilles.town/" target=_blank>Merveilles</a> webring. I had been thinking about developing something like that for the indienet for sometime now, so coming across it was super cool.</p>

<p>I really like the concept of webrings and personal websites. The lartunet is part of the <a href="https://emreed.net/LowTech_Directory.html" target=_blank>Low Tech Webring</a>. I may create my own webring in the future. That'd be very nice, but for now, I kept exploring what Merveilles had to offer. It has some amazing people with amazing websites.</p>

<p>This whole cyber-adventure took me to the <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com" target=_blank>Low Tech Magazine</a>, a website that runs on solar power alone. I also found <a href="https://github.com/MaggieAppleton/digital-gardeners" target=_blank>this list of digital gardens</a>. I haven't had the time to check it thoroughly yet, be my guest at that.</p>

<p>What I like about most indienet websites I've found is that they are quite enriching. Their content is really something else. Personal photos, ideas, stories; it's like hopping inside their owners' heads. Unlike most mainstream websites out there, I feel that when I visit one of these sites I leave with more than I had when I entered. It's a very positive experience.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_E96G81.JPEG" title="E96G81" alt="Image: E96G81"><small>— E96G81  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/E96G81.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1641 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>I also read a <a href="https://hieroglyph.asu.edu/2014/09/solarpunk-notes-toward-a-manifesto/" target=_blank>Solarpunk Manifesto</a>. There are others out there, apparently, too. This article about <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2016/11/why-the-office-needs-a-typewriter-revolution.html" target=_blank>Low Tech Offices</a> was also very interesting.</p>

<p>Finally, I spent some time thinking about the things I learned this week. I learned about Bash scripting, about configuring <code>iptables</code>, about freedom of press and expression in Latin America (and, in particular, in Argentina). I wrote some code in <a href="https://ldpl-lang.org" target=_blank>LDPL</a>, after a year or more of not doing so. It's clunky. In some ways it's like C. You have to reinvent the wheel every time you want to do something, or do it frequently enough to have your own set of libraries and tools already reinvented. These are not languages built to make stuff fast that breaks fast. They are designed to write stable code that works well. It takes longer, but the result does what it has to do. It's stable, solid and efficient. Maybe that's what's beautiful about them.</p>

<h1>03J21</h1>

<p>Today I had a law test. I passed it with a wonderful grade. I had studied much more than it was needed, really, but I would be lying if I said I didn't enjoy somewhat what I was studying.</p>

<p>To celebrate, I went to McDonald's and had some McNuggets. McDonald's is not precisely cheap here, quite on the contrary. It's much cheaper to buy fresh begetables and meat. I was so hungry I didn't take any pictures, but the day was gray and cold and lovely. For dinner, I had boiled carrots and potatoes. Super tasty.</p>

<p>I bought a new bluetooth mouse that can be connected to two computers at the same time and switch between them with the click of a button. I work with two computers at the same time, so I needed something like this.</p>

<p>My shoulder's a little better. I can take the cast off now and then, but it still hurts. Sleeping without it is impossible.</p>

<p><img src="https://lartu.net/images/c_D50S00.JPEG" title="D50S00" alt="Image: D50S00"></p>

<p>Some days before I had begun growing some carrots. By this day, they had already grown tiny leaves. My minuscule orange islands.</p>

<p>The rest of the day was spent studying.</p>

<p>I still have eleven days to talk about, but I think I will split this entry here because it's getting way too long and I have some more immediate things to do. I will be back with another anthology entry soon enough. Thank you for reading!</p>]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Outdoors &amp; Curry</title>
			<link>https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-28.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink='false'>log_2021-05-28.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:56:00 -0300</pubDate>
			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lartu]]></dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<!-- RSS ARTICLE STARTS HERE -->
<h1>2021-05-28: outdoors & curry.</h1>

<p>This is a double log, because I fell asleep when I was supposed to write yesterday's log entry. It's not much of a deal, though. Today's entry is heavily connected with that one. Two for the price of one.</p>

<p>Also, this entry is going to be in full colour. I like the colours of the pictures I've taken to go with it, and turning on the grayscale filter wouldn't do them any justice.</p>

<h2>yesterday.</h2>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_T19U70.JPEG" title="T19U70" alt="Image: T19U70"><small>— T19U70  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/T19U70.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2649 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>First of all, the leek has grown even more. In fact, now I am a little worried that living in water will not suit it anymore, so later today I'm going to see if I can get it a proper pot for it to lay roots in.</p>

<p>Also, I've started trying to grow a carrot. Apparently like growing a single specimen per vegetable.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_T89O61.JPEG" title="T89O61" alt="Image: T89O61"><small>— T89O61  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/T89O61.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2183 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>I had this little can of <b>S&B Spicy Curry</b> I'd brought from Japan as a souvenir and I was feeling up for some karēraisu, so I decided I'd make some for dinner.</p>

<p>This is not instant curry, but rather normal -albeit somewhat spicy- curry powder. Locally bought spice would've served just fine, but I already had this one, so I'd figured why not use it.</p>

<p>In the end, it seems that the secret was not in the curry itself, but in the recipe. I've made curry in the past, but it was never this good. However, I had never followed a curry recipe like the one on this can. My Japanese is less than perfect, but it's good enough to read it. That was a surprise for me, by the way. I didn't thought I'd be able to understand anything, but alas, the curry was cooked just fine.</p>

<p>In that same topic, during the 2020 pandemic lockdown I began following multiple Japanese accounts on <a href="https://twitter.com/martulartu" target=_blank>Twitter</a>. That ended up being an amazing choice. My Japanese improved a tad by reading those tiny chunks of text. Kanji are still quite the trouble, though, so I use <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/rikaikun/jipdnfibhldikgcjhfnomkfpcebammhp" target=_blank><b>Rikaikun</b></a> (Chrome / Edge / Firefox) or <a href="https://apps.apple.com/ar/app/safarikai/id1437951175" target=_blank><b>Safarikai</b></a> (Safari) to get their readings on the fly. Great tools, cannot recommend they enough if you are struggling with the language.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_U17D97.JPEG" title="U17D97" alt="Image: U17D97"><small>— U17D97  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/U17D97.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2771 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>For lunch we had patties with chopped onions and sauerkraut we made from red cabbage some weeks ago. It was easily the best part of the dish. If you want to learn to prepare some for yourself, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mUwC7bTjLkQ" target=_blank>this video</a> explains the process very well.</p>

<p>After lunch, I spent some time reading the <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/gnu-c-manual/gnu-c-manual.pdf" target=_blank><b>GNU C Manual</b></a>. It's a rather pleasant read so far. I want to improve my C, this is the first step. <a href="https://www.libsdl.org" target=_blank>SDL2</a>, you are next!</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_D12X40.JPEG" title="D12X40" alt="Image: D12X40"><small>— D12X40  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/D12X40.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2393 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>We spent the better part of the afternoon working and studying outside in the patio. The weather wasn't hot nor cold, so it was perfect for spending some time breathing fresh air.</p>

<p>While doing an assignment for college, I learned to configure RAID disk redundance using <code>mdadm</code> and virtual partitions using LVM. I knew those things existed, but I didn't know how to set them up myself. Now I do, and it's way easier than I had expected. The <a href="https://debian-handbook.info/browse/en-US/stable/advanced-administration.html" target=_blank>Debian Administrator's Handbook</a> explains the process in detailed, yet easy to follow steps.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_Q32O72.JPEG" title="Q32O72" alt="Image: Q32O72"><small>— Q32O72  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/Q32O72.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2217 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>For dinner, following the recipe in the can, I made curry. It's a really simple dish, to I'd expect it to be more involved.</p>

<p><b>Curry Recipe</b></p>

<p>Take a big <b>potato</b> and a middle-sized <b>carrot</b> (the recipe says small carrot, but we only had middle-to-big ones). Dice them. Then take an <b>onion</b> and dice it. If you eat meat, get some <b>meat</b> and dice it too.</p>

<p>Take a pan and with little <b>oil</b> (4-6 tablespoons) fry half of the diced onions until they are brown. Then add the carrot, potato and meat to the pan and fry them a little too. Then add 700ml of <b>water</b> and a <b>stock cube</b> (I used a vegetable-flavored one) to the pan and let it boil.</p>

<p>While that's cooking, take the other half of the diced onions and put them on a frying pan with again 4 to 6 tablespoons of oil. Fry them while adding 4 to 10 tablespoons of <b>wheat</b> until the onions are brown. The can, again, says 4 tablespoons, but either my spoons are too tiny or my Japanese is not up to the task, because 4 tablespoons of wheat didn't seem like enough. Anyway, add 4 tablespoons of <b>curry powder</b> to the wheaty onions, mix them well and add the wheat-onion-curry concoction to the pan where the vegetables and meat are boiling.</p>

<p>Cook until the vegetables are soft and the meat is cooked and the consistence of the liquid is right (liquid but kinda mushy). Add salt and pepper to taste and serve on white rice.</p>

<p>(You can also find this recipe in the <a href="https://lartu.net/cookbook.coso" target=_blank>cookbook</a>.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_I77A74.JPEG" title="I77A74" alt="Image: I77A74"><small>— I77A74  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/I77A74.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1957 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>It was amazing. Oh my, I cannot stress enough how much I like curry. I ate like three plates, then fell asleep for hours.</p>

<h2>today.</h2>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_W29U44.JPEG" title="W29U44" alt="Image: W29U44"><small>— W29U44  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/W29U44.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1393 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>Today I went back to the patio, set up a table and worked from there. The sky was blue and almost clear. Under the sun, the cold autumn weather was no more and I had to take my sweater off. Nice for a change!</p>

<p>Of course, we had leftover curry for lunch.</p>

<p>In other news, I'm still reading <b>The Catcher in the Rye</b>, by J. D. Salinger. It's taking me too long to finish it. I've not been able to set time apart for reading. I usually read in bed, but lately I end up the day so tired that I fall asleep immediately.</p>

<p>I am, however, attempting something new with my sleep patterns. Since the day before yesterday, I've been following a biphasic sleep pattern, meaning that I sleep for some hours, then wake up in the middle of the night, do stuff and then go back to sleep again.</p>

<p>What I've found out so far is that, first, I wake up well rested in the morning. And second, that during those hours in-between naps I'm very focused and relaxed. This allows me to study or work without distractions, which I enjoy. Yesterday I spent some hours adding houses to the Stonehollow town of <a href="https://eterspire.com" target=_blank>Eterspire</a> Beta II. It's looking quite alright! Today I'll carry on with that.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_N07Y51.JPEG" title="N07Y51" alt="Image: N07Y51"><small>— N07Y51  (JPEG) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/N07Y51.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2140 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>After writing all of that, I went out and bought a pot and dirt for the leek. It's now planted outside. There, everyone happy!</p>]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Farmers' Market</title>
			<link>https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-25.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink='false'>log_2021-05-25.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 21:36:00 -0300</pubDate>
			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lartu]]></dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<!-- RSS ARTICLE STARTS HERE -->
<h1>2021-05-25: farmers' market.</h1>

<p>I had been looking forward to this day for almost a week. There's a farmers' market that gathers a few blocks from home every Tuesday and I was very excited to visit them. The experience was, unfortunately, somewhat lackluster.</p>

<p>The place was well stocked, but there were very few stalls. I had been to markets like this in the past, and those had more booths. This time, that wasn't the case. Maybe because of the pandemic and the lockdown.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_M93R95.gif" title="M93R95" alt="Image: M93R95"><small>— M93R95 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/M93R95.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (3221 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>One man got mad at me for taking pictures of the place. I realize I should've asked before taking any, but my mind was somewhere else. It's not that I was shooting pictures of him either. In any case, that didn't give the market any extra points.</p>

<p>My original idea was to go there and buy groceries for the whole week. My usual shops stock the same stuff they sell, however, and I'd rather continue supporting them, so I don't believe my shopping habits will change a bit. Which is a little disappointing because I was looking for something new.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_J75U74.gif" title="J75U74" alt="Image: J75U74"><small>— J75U74 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/J75U74.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2888 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>The leek I started growing some days ago has grown a lot! We were quite surprised at this. I don't know the first thing about plants, so I was expecting it to grow at a much slower pace. Nature is amazing.</p>

<p>I also put on, for the first time, a pair of socks I'd bought in Australia about two years ago. They are decorated with jelly beans. I love colorful socks. When I moved by myself, I left the plain-colored pairs behind, so now my feet are always clad in pretty patterns.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_P68I55.gif" title="P68I55" alt="Image: P68I55"><small>— P68I55 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/P68I55.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2110 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>On the way home I saw a flock of pidgeons sitting on a phone line. Their picture ended up looking like a lost Windows 7 wallpaper. You can click <i>view original</i> to open the picture in full colour and see what I mean.</p>

<p>I then went to visit my parents. We had lunch together (sitting at tables set 3 meters apart and wearing face-masks when not eating). This time, I had new things to tell them! Amazing, just what I was hoping for.</p>

<p>After that, we spent time together and had some cups of coffee. I went back home at around eight in the evening. The block across the street was bursting with policemen and police cars. I don't know what was going on, and I didn't really feel like asking. But I'm very intrigued nonetheless.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_G83Q60.gif" title="G83Q60" alt="Image: G83Q60"><small>— G83Q60 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/G83Q60.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (3069 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>We held a Zoom meeting with Tejo to discuss the coming development sprints for <a href="https://eterspire.com" target=_blank>Eterspire Beta II</a>. That's tasks for the next eight weeks. Done that, the game should be finished and -if not already released-, ready to ship.</p>

<p>When we hang up, I had a nap, ate dinner and rewrote the whole script I use to compile the Lartunet. It's much more scalable and maintainable now. It also supports RSS, so you can get my ramblings and updates directly into your favourite reader. I'm using <a href="http://netnewswire.com" target=_blank>NetNewsWire</a> and I like it very much. It's free and open-source, but it only works on iDevices.</p>



<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_J77A10.gif" title="J77A10" alt="Image: J77A10"><small>— J77A10 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/J77A10.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (3109 KiB, JPG)</small></p>]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Worldbuilding</title>
			<link>https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-24.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink='false'>log_2021-05-24.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lartu]]></dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<!-- RSS ARTICLE STARTS HERE -->

<h1>2021-05-24: worldbuilding.</h1>

<p>With my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/tejo240" target=_blank>Tejo</a>, we are working on this indie MMORPG called <a href="https://eterspire.com" target=_blank>Eterspire</a>. We are very close to releasing the second open-beta of the game. We are so excited about that!</p>

<p>I began developing Eterspire by myself in October last year. I've always wanted to make my own MMORPG! And so I did. I believe it was in February that I released the first beta. A lot of people signed up. Much fun was had. The game, however, was very limited, so I joined forces with Tejo to work on a second version. We spent the past four months tweaking the engine, adding new features and fixing my less-than-ideal code. And yesterday, we completed the last non-content-releated task, so today we met to discuss the actual content of the game. The world, its inhabitants, quests, treasures and monsters.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_H43G34.gif" title="H43G34" alt="Image: H43G34"><small>— H43G34 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/H43G34.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1622 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>We had an amazing time, ate lunch and brainstormed the weirdest ideas.</p>

<p>He has a cute, tiny cat. She spent the afternoon with us, too.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_A02N98.gif" title="A02N98" alt="Image: A02N98"><small>— A02N98 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/A02N98.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1761 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>At around 5 PM, the final sketches for the world were complete, so I left Tejo's house. On the way back to my apartment, I heard somebody calling me. <i>Could you lend us a hand?</i>, they said.</p>

<p>The calling voice was that of a mechanic from a car repair shop. His associates and him needed help pushing a car up a ramp and into their workshop. I grouped with them, along with an old-man that was also passing-by, and we got the vehicle into their shop. Fun! While not something <i>that</i> out of the ordinary, this was the kind of experience I was looking forward for. For a moment, I met new people and did something I never do in my usual routine. I regret not taking a picture with them for this article, but I didn't want to be a nuisance. Next time I will.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_L74E46.gif" title="L74E46" alt="Image: L74E46"><small>— L74E46 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/L74E46.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (3538 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>The leaves on the street scattered by the storm from <a href="https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-22.html" >the other day</a> were still there, although it seemed somebody had been cleaning them up. Autumn.</p>

<p>When I got home, I fired up my computer and began turning the ideas we'd discussed about into a reality. We are so close to the release, yet there's still so much to do. I can barely wait.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_M81A84.gif" title="M81A84" alt="Image: M81A84"><small>— M81A84 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/M81A84.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (3964 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>Tomorrow we are going to a farmers' market and I'll meet my family for lunch afterwards, with strict sanitary precautions. I hope after all of that I'll have something new to write about.</p>]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Walking Around</title>
			<link>https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-23.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink='false'>log_2021-05-23.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lartu]]></dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<!-- RSS ARTICLE STARTS HERE -->

<h1>2021-05-23: walking around.</h1>

<p>Second day in a row I'm writting in this log. Don't get used to it, but here's to keeping doing stuff now and then.</p>

<p>Today I had some free time, so I decided to go out and walk a little with no destination in mind. I just chose a road and walked to see what I could find. And find new things I did, which is always something good. Sadly, it wasn't drizzling anymore. I like when it does.</p>

<p>My original idea was to go out and buy some take-away coffee. While at home, I had cooked myself a plate of half-English mess, that's half a full English breakfast, without the English part and half the dish, so I wasn't feeling up for coffee anymore. I just went out for the walking part.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_L29P12.gif" title="L29P12" alt="Image: L29P12"><small>— L29P12 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/L29P12.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1330 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>A few blocks away from home I stopped at a plant shop. I wanted to buy a pot and some dirt for the leek I started growing <a href="https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-22.html" >yesterday</a>, but due to the lockdown you couldn't go into the store, so I took note of their website to check their stock later. They sell pretty pretty pots.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_X97R90.gif" title="X97R90" alt="Image: X97R90"><small>— X97R90 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/X97R90.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (3271 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>From there, I kept walking aimlessly. The streets were empty and quite silent. I like that. Also they were covered by leaves from yesterday's rain. I found an old storage building with a crane atop. I had never seen it. I have not seen many things in my neighbourhood. That's part of the reason I'm trying to go out more.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_M02T44.gif" title="M02T44" alt="Image: M02T44"><small>— M02T44 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/M02T44.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2123 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>Then I found a bar that looked quite nice. Of course, I hadn't been there before. When the people from the bar saw me taking photos of their shop, a waiter came out and gave me a take-away menu of the place. Great service. I may buy food there in the future.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_C83I31.gif" title="C83I31" alt="Image: C83I31"><small>— C83I31 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/C83I31.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2743 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>They also had a very pretty, old-school round sign outside. I don't know if I'd classify the place as a <i>bar</i> per sé, but the sign said bar, so that's the nomenclature I'm using.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_I03E58.gif" title="I03E58" alt="Image: I03E58"><small>— I03E58 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/I03E58.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1130 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>After that, I kept wandering about. I passed by a drug store and bought some antihistamines. If there's something I'm allergic to, it's every single thing. And I was running out, so that was a nice stop. I also bought a handheld electric massager. It was on sale and I like those things. I haven't tried it yet, though.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_V11W88.gif" title="V11W88" alt="Image: V11W88"><small>— V11W88 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/V11W88.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1224 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>Overall it was a very nice walk, I came back home refreshed and ready to carry on studying. Tomorrow we meet with the Eterspire development team to begin working on the content sprint. An afternoon spent world-building, a dream come true! And hopefully, an interesting day to talk about.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_I39U11.gif" title="I39U11" alt="Image: I39U11"><small>— I39U11 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/I39U11.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (2855 KiB, JPG)</small></p>]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pickles and Rain</title>
			<link>https://lartu.net/log_2021-05-22.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink='false'>log_2021-05-22.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lartu]]></dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<!-- RSS ARTICLE STARTS HERE -->

<h1>2021-05-22: pickles and rain.</h1>

<p>Yesterday I read <a href="https://www.raptitude.com/2010/07/your-lifestyle-has-already-been-designed/" target=_blank>this article</a> about how our routines (working all day and having a little free time during the evening) are functional to consumerism. It may be that way. It may not, I don't really care much. What I do care about is that <i>that's</i> my routine. Every day the same four walls, same activities, same everything.</p>

<p>This is not the first time I've noticed this, though. I visited my grandparents about two months ago after a long year of not seeing them during the 2020 quarantine. I had a lot of stuff to tell them: I had moved by myself, I was cooking a lot, I had started taking classes in a new university, etc. Lots of changes and news.</p>

<p>Then, a month later, I visited them again. This time, I had nothing new to tell.</p>

<p>The same goes for visiting my parents. I see them once a week or so. When I moved by myself I had a lot of things to tell them. Then, week after week, nothing. I cooked some stuff, I went to the same old shops, work, sleep, study. Eternal while true. I struggled trying to find something to talk about. What's next? I could do a lot more, why am I not doing so?</p>

<p>Well, I believe the main impediment right now is the COVID-19 pandemic. We've been quarantined. Again. And traveling abroad is not particularly easy at this very moment. I live in a big city, though. There <i>should</i> be things to do around here! Why am I not partaking in that? Then again, the answer is the pandemic.</p>

<p>In any case, though, there are other things I should be able to do to break the monotony. So I've started this log. I will try to do something new now and then. And who knows, maybe I'll be able to escape the oppressive cycle my life has turned into.</p>

<p>So, <b>what did I do today?</b></p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_M72J76.gif" title="M72J76" alt="Image: M72J76"><small>— M72J76 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/M72J76.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1289 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>Today it rained a lot. There's a cyclone alert and everything. Sadly, I didn't take any pictures. I didn't know I was going to write a log of my day. In any case, given that we are to be quarantined -and thanks to the weather- the streets were rather empty. We went to the grocery store taking the longest possible route, seizing the opportunity to discover our neighbourhood. I love the way everything shines when it rains.</p>

<p>We even found some dumbells somebody had discarded on the street, so we took them home. They were in perfect shape!</p>

<p>We came back home wet and cold after buying some veggies. I cooked some soup and baked pumpkin, and we ate it outside in the patio, under the rain-turned-drizzle. Cool experience.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_I03C35.gif" title="I03C35" alt="Image: I03C35"><small>— I03C35 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/I03C35.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1315 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>Having eaten and all, I pickled some onions and peppers and left them in a cupboard to marinate. In a week or two they'll be ready to eat.</p>

<p><img  src="https://lartu.net/images/c_Y43C23.gif" title="Y43C23" alt="Image: Y43C23"><small>— Y43C23 (b&w version) (quantized 16C) - <a href="https://lartu.net/images/Y43C23.JPG"  target=_blank>view original</a> (1805 KiB, JPG)</small></p>

<p>I'm growing a leek. The rest of it went into the soup. Once it grows new roots I'll plant it in a pot.</p>

<p>Also, I started reading <i>The Catcher in the Rye</i>, by J. D. Salinger. My uncle had recommended it to me many times. He had even lent me his copy at some point. I hadn't had the chance to read it, though. I'm walfway through. Great book, the way it's written reminds me a lot of how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Night_in_the_Woods" target=_blank>Night in the Woods</a> is written. That's never a bad thing.</p>

<p>Tomorrow I will try to go out and walk a little more. I can't go out for <i>too long</i> because we've been requested to stay at home, but somewhere close should be fine. Maybe to a park or to get some take-away coffee.</p>]]></description>
		</item>
</channel></rss>